Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1980/81, XIV.
  - Provost and Senior Vice Chancellor, 1980-1981; 7.0.
    - Fine Arts, Memoranda Regarding Organ (Box 12, Folder 7.3f)
    - Honors Program (Box 12, Folder 7.3g)
    - Music and Heinz Chapel Choir (Box 13, Folder 7.3h)
      Funding for Heinz Chapel Choir, March 10, 1981; General University Fund, February 1981; 1981 tour of Pennsylvania now in planning for the Heinz Chapel Choir; "Music: Stock Turns Talents to Dance Music" by Capone; "Pittsburgh Ensemble in Series of Premieres," May 3, 1981; "Pittsburgh's People: An Ethnic Music Celebration"; and Gift of album "Leopold Stokowski Conducting the Philadelphia Orchestra 1931-1932" to the music library.
    - Langley Hall Fire (Box 13, Folder 7.3i)
    - Speech and Theatre Arts (Box 13, Folder 7.3k)
      Two productions from Pitt named in Anderson's News article, "Favorites of year in theater," June 2, 1981; Newman Lecture "Joe McCarthy and the Nixon syndrome"; Article, "Foreword: Antitrust on the Campus Debate Circuit," February 3, 1981; William Pitt Debating Union wins first place in the "California Swing" debate tournaments, January 9, 1981; Clippings of the success of the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, September 15, 1980; and Commendation for Matthews, Favorini, Melia, Katz, and George in their contributions in the writing of the book Rhythm in Drama published by the University of Pittsburgh Press.
    - Political Science, Falk Chair (Box 13, Folder 7.3l)
    - Economics (Box 13, Folder 7.3m)
      Commendation to Kenkel for his book Introductory Statistics for Management and Economics, June 16, 1981; Posvar Remarks on the AAUP draft Statement on Collegiality and Faculty Governance, March 31, 1981; Whitman's resignation as Distinguished Public Service Professor of Economics, June 5, 1981; Thorn elected President of the local AAUP Chapter, October 16, 1980; and Letters of concern from Economics department Faculty and graduate students regarding the decision to move Economics Department Library from its present location to Hillman Library.
    - Wallace, Magnetism and Hydrogen Fuel (Box 13, Folder 7.3n)
      Conference on Cooperative Advances in Chemical Science and Technology, April 24, 1981; Proposed Formation of a Chemical Research Council, February 23, 1981; Wallace letter to President Reagan concerning incentives for fostering technological innovation; Suggestion of a format for the Chemical Industries Research Fund, September 27, 1980; NSF Research Equipment Grant, February 12, 1981; Requesting necessary funds to develop a surface science center, February 5, 1981; Union Oil and Pitt's Supermagnet Development; Major Breakthrough in our Magnetics Research Program, October 28, 1980; Goal achieved and exceeded of producing a 20 Million Gauss-Oersted permanent magnet material which did not contain samarium, October 28, 1980.
    - Chemistry, Graduate Study (Box 13, Folder 7.3o)
    - FAS Pamphlets (Box 13, Folder 7.3p)
      "Classics and Philosophy at the University of Pittsburgh; "Community Organization and Planning, School of Social Work, University of Pittsburgh"; "Computer Science, University of Pittsburgh"; "Graduate Study in English, University of Pittsburgh"; "Graduate Study in Composition, University of Pittsburgh"; "M.F.A. in Writing, University of Pittsburgh"; "Philosophy, University of Pittsburgh"; and "University of Pittsburgh Theater presents Beauty and the Beast."
    - Polish Studies (Box 13, Folder 7.3q)
    - Surface Science Center (Box 13, Folder 7.3r)
      PRMS for Surface Science Center, April 14, 1981; Summary of objectives for the Surface Science Center, June 1, 1981; Division of Colloid and Surface Chemistry, Proposed Industrial Sponsored Fellowships in Surface Chemistry and Physics; and "Contingent Liabilities for Surface Science Figures are in Thousands of Dollars."
    - FAS Chairs Meeting, April 23, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 7.3s)
    - FAS Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 7.3t)
      Letters concerning the consideration of Jack Walker as a candidate for the Falk Chair of American Politics; Continuing relationship between Gulf, RIDC and Chemistry Department, February 9, 1981; Sculpture in the Hillman Library; Annual Report of Academic Activities from Rescher for the 1979-1980 Academic Year; Commendation to Newman for efforts as a Visiting Scientist in the Legislative Office for Research Liaison, October 3, 1980; Proposed Occupancy of the Cathedral of Learning; Meeting with chairmen of the foreign language departments; Report of the Managing Editor, Journal of Economic Literature; American Mathematical Society and the Mathematical Association of America's acceptance of invitation to hold their joint summer meeting on campus, October 31, 1980; Asian Council Luncheon, October 22, 1980; Letter to Mare from Sussman Regarding teaching assignments for the coming academic year, February 16, 1981.
    - Michel Thomas Language Centers (Box 13, Folder 7.3u - 7.3v)
    - FAS - Board of Visitors (Box 14, Folder 7.3w)
    - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) (Box 14, Folder 7.4)
      Foreign Language and Culture Study; Approval of Undergraduate Major in Microbiology, November 26, 1980; and Department of Education Site Visit, November 25, 1980.
    - Report of the Subcommittee on Goals to the Committee on Curriculum Reform, College of Arts and Sciences, February 9, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 7.4a)
    - CAS - Board of Visitors (Box 14, Folder 7.4b)
    - CAS Advising Center (Box 14, Folder 7.4c)
    - Support Service Office, Student Affairs for Athletes (Box 14, Folder 7.4d)
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (FAS) (Box 14, Folder 7.5)
      Grater's acceptance of Posvar's invitation to give the Distinguished Lecture Series next year, July 11, 1980, and Conference Board of Associated Research Councils undertaking the task of initiating as national study to evaluate the characteristics and effectiveness of research-doctorate programs in the United States, September 8, 1980.
    - Graduate School of Business (Box 14, Folder 7.6)
      Challenges of Developing A Contemporary Graduate School of Business Building; Information about Graduate School of Business Programs, Board of Visitors Meeting, March 27, 1981; Board of Visitors Membership; Report of the Board of Visitors for the Graduate School of Business, March 27, 1981; Continuing Education Facilities, May 11, 1981; MPE Tuition Increase, May 19, 1981; CLIPS, Graduate School of Business University of Pittsburgh newspaper; Planning and construction of a new building for the Graduate School of Business on the site along Robert Clemente Drive, March 3, 1981; Funding for the Proposed Graduate School of Business Building, February 24, 1981; The Business School Physical Facilities, July 10, 1980; Management Science Study, March 6, 1980; The Center for Economic Education, University of Pittsburgh; and Report of the BOV Meeting for the Graduate School of Business, June 11, 1981.
    - Proposed CAS-Business Dual Degree (Box 14, Folder 7.6a)
      Study funded through the Director of Planning and Research for the Japan Economic Journal, July 16, 1980; Conference on Coal Gasification, Liquefaction, and Conversion to Electricity, July 28, 1980; Synergy, The Graduate School of Business Newsletter; Presenting CEOs of Pittsburgh area companies with plaques to recognize their commitment to the Business School, August 1, 1980; Master's Degree in Interdisciplinary Studies, September 9, 1980; "The Chief Executive Encounters The Business Student, VII"; and Formal mechanism for promoting relationship between the University and the industrial community.
    - Higher Education Program (Box 14, Folder 7.7)
      University of Pittsburgh Higher Education Program Faculty, September 3, 1980; Report of Graduate Studies Committee Actions, July 31, 1980; University of Pittsburgh Higher Education Program Faculty Meetings; Tita will be appointed as a Kent Post-Doctoral Fellow under the joint sponsorship of the University of Pittsburgh and the University of Southern California, July 25, 1980; Ways to operationalize the University's commitment in the International area, July 16, 1980; and Graduate School of Business Board of Visitors Terms of Office.
    - School of Education (Box 14, Folder 7.7a)
      Higher Education Program Agenda, Faculty Meetings; Proposed Design for Professional Education and Certification in Pennsylvania; University of Pittsburgh School of Education Alumni Newsletters; Management Development Questionnaire, April 29, 1981; "School of Education Enrollment, Faculty, and Budget Information for 1977-1981"; Comments on Master Degree Program in Higher Education, April 1, 1981; Preliminary and Comprehensive Examinations for the Ph.D. and Ed.D., February 23, 1981; School of Education Faculty Council Minutes; Identification of Potential Learning Experiences and Faculty Resources in Gerontology, February 26, 1981; Higher Education Program Post-Core Curriculum Meeting, February 9, 1981; "Reaction Paper to the Report of an Initial Review of the Supervisor of Vocational Education Program," January 23, 1981; School of Education Fall Faculty Assembly, December 12, 1980; Notification of the accreditation of the Rehabilitation Counselor Education Program, October 10, 1980; Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of Education, Bureau of Academic Programs to Teacher Educators, Official Contact Persons and Deans of Education, September 1980; Report on Reevaluation of Approved Graduate Certificate Program of Teacher of Library Science Program, September 1980; Report of Initial Review of Supervisor of School Library Media Program; and Report on the Pittsburgh Public School Supervisor's Workshop, July 23, 1980.
    - International Studies (Box 14, Folder 7.7b)
      "Education and the World View," Preliminary Draft of a Paper on the Role of Colleges and Universities in Relationship to International Affairs by Posvar; "Globalizing the Undergraduate Experience," by Posvar, March 26, 1980; "International Education," by Spaulding, Colucci, and Flint, April 1981; Meeting of Deans with Minority Concerns; Congratulations to Kelly on being honored with the title of Fellow of the College of Preceptors at the University of London Institute of Education, June 25, 1981; Graduate Study Committee Report; Draft Report from Committee on Masters Degree, May 26, 1981; "What's Higher About Higher Education," by Cleveland, Hubert Humphrey Institute for Public Affairs, March 6, 1981; Report on National Center for Education Statistics Meeting Concerning the Higher Education General Information Survey to All College and University Presidents Proprietary School Directors, May 22, 1981; Proposed Legislation, Educational Block Grants-Elementary and Secondary Education Consolidation Act of 1981; Approved Teaching Intern Certification Program, May 22, 1981; and NCATE Update, National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, "The Economics of NCATE Accreditation."
    - School of Engineering (Box 15, Folder 7.8)
      Report to the Board of Visitors, 1980-1981; School of Engineering Board of Visitors Meeting, April 6, 1981; "Planning Proposal for the Cooperative Education Program in the School of Engineering" by Colclaser and Hoelzeman, April 6, 1981; 1981 Report to the Board of Visitors; School of Engineering List of Faculty; Educational Aid Committee to continue the RCA Scholarship in Engineering the University of Pittsburgh, April 14, 1981; Congratulations to Meiksin for his Recent receipt of a patent for the invention, "Discontinuous Metal Film Resistor and Strain Gauges"; Coal research, March 16, 1981; Atlantic Richfield's decision to award several grants to Petroleum Engineering and Chemical Engineering, August 1, 1980; Marshall Goldberg Proposal; Commendation to Yates on the expert assistance that he provided to Kroner, Superintendent of Allegheny County Police, and his staff in their criminal investigation of an arson in White Oak Boro, June 25, 1981; Reporting the use of Allied Chemical money for 1980-1981; Pitt Engineering Alumni Association inaugurates new program "Awareness 80's," September 12, 1980; Department of Chemical and Petroleum Engineering received $4,000 from the Du Pont Science and Engineering Grant, January 15, 1981; "The Engineering Bulletin," March 9, 1981; Al-Jishi, Moore and Czapor received the Distinguished Alumnus award, February 23, 1981; University Liability under the Export Controls Act, March 13, 1980; Eighth Annual International Conference on Coal Gasification, Liquefaction, and Conversion to Electricity, July 20, 1981; Chemical and Petroleum Engineering Department received a $5,000 grant from the Exxon Education Foundation, July 6, 1981; Budget Review FY1982; Letters on problems of encouraging venture capital in Pittsburgh; and Mining Engineering Division, University of Pittsburgh, "Mine Productivity in a Safe Environment: a proposed 5 Year Research Development Plan".
    - School of Engineering - Board of Visitors (Box 15, Folder 7.8a)
      School of Engineering Board of Visitors Meeting, Orientation, April 6, 1981; "Planning the Proposal for the Cooperative Education Program in the School of Engineering" by Colcaser and Hoelzeman; 1981 Report to the Board of Visitors; and Graphs of Granted Bachelors, Masters, Doctorate Degrees of Engineering.
    - College of General Studies (CGS) (Box 15, Folder 7.9)
      Approval of a Part-Time Day Program to be offered by the College of General Studies, November 6, 1980; College of General Studies Report, October 16, 1980; College of General Studies Board of Visitors Members and Meetings; Article, "The Colonial Penn Elder Scholars Program," June 10, 1980; Night Student Parking Permits, August 28, 1980; and article on Sapienza, February 1981.
    - Office of Student Cabinet, New CGS Logo (Box 15, Folder 7.9a)
    - Elder Scholar Program, New CGS Logo (Box 15, Folder 7.9b)
    - CGS - Board of Visitors (Box 15, Folder 7.9c)
      Membership; Reports; Guidelines from central administration concerning the allocation of scarce resources, June 23, 1981; Update on the Downtown Information Center, April 1, 1981; Proposal, The Chancellor's Scholarship Program for CGS Students, May 15, 1981; Western Penitentiary Program, May 28, 1981; and Memo to Presidents of Pennsylvania Colleges and Universities regarding External Masters Degree Program.
    - School of Law (Box 15, Folder 7.10.)
      The Law School's admissions racial policy, May 26, 1981; Alternatives to the Provost's new policy on not listing racial data, May 22, 1981; Law School Accreditation, January 26, 1981; Board of Visitors Membership; College of General Studies annual report, July 1, 1979 - June 30, 1980; and Letters concerning Law School Admissions.
    - School of Library and Information Science (SLIS) (Box 15, Folder 7.11)
      Congratulatory letter to Kimmel for being elected to the Office of Vice President/President Elect of the Association for Library Service to Children, July 6, 1981; Congratulatory letter to Wright for being elected to a four year term as member of the Council of the American Library Association, July 2, 1981; Teaching Faculty Meeting Minutes; "Perceptions by Educators and Administrators of the Ranking of Library School Programs"; "An Information and Referral Center at the University of Pittsburgh: A Refinement in Two Parts" by Firth and Micco, January 1980; Approval of Drug Information Specialist Dual Master's Degree Program, July 14, 1980; and SLIS Faculty Activities 1979-1980.
    - SLIS - Board of Visitors (Box 15, Folder 7.11a)
      Board of Visitors Members; Papers of Cardinal Wright, August 13, 1980; Special Meeting of Teaching Faculty, December 5, 1980; Congratulations to Walgren on his designation as Chairman of the House Science, Research and Technology Subcommittee, February 19, 1981; Evaluation of Library Schools; Data concerning minority student enrollment trends in the School of Library and Information Science, March 18, 1981; "Perceptions by Educators and Administrators of the Ranking of Library School Programs"; "An Information and Referral Center at the University of Pittsburgh A Refinement in Two Parts" by Firth, January 1980; and SLIS Faculty Activities 1979-1980.
    - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (GSPIA) (Box 16)
      Salary Increase Guideline for FY1982, April 28, 1981; Presidential Management Intern Program, April 1981; Congratulations to Funari and members of faculty and staff for achieving recognition by the National Association of Schools of Public Affairs/Administration, March 31, 1981; National Standing of GSPIA, March 6, 1981; Problems associated with cross-listing of courses and accounting for student credit hours, March 3, 1981; and Commendation to Funari on publication outlining the various programs and the history of GSPIA, February 23, 1981.
    - University Libraries (Box 16, Folder 7.14)
      Library Budget Problems, November 13, 1980; Report by Pitt's Task Force on University Libraries, April 10, 1981; Excerpt from the Minutes of the Senate Council Meeting Relative to University Libraries Discussion, June 1980; Minutes of the Senate Council Meeting, May 12, 1980; Journal subscriptions for the Natural Science Libraries Journal subscriptions for the Natural Science Libraries, June 16, 1980; University of Pittsburgh Hillman Library System Acquisition Expenditures; Article, "The Future of Academic Libraries: The Inevitability of Change"; and Memo regarding Library Crisis Article, "Shrinking Library Budget Stirs Up Faculty," October 15, 1980.
    - Financial Aid Application for University to Participate in Federal Student Aid Programs (Box 16, Folder 7.15)
    - Weekly Admissions Report (Box 16, Folder 7.15a)
      "Analysis of freshman applicant population and completion of two or more years in the same language: Survey of Secondary Schools in Pittsburgh Area, Foreign Language Graduation Requirement, Other Comparable Universities, and PCHE"; Cooperative Institution Research Program, March 24, 1981; Congratulatory letter to Merante for the Office of Admissions and Financial Aid receiving the Direct Mail Marketing Association ECHO award, January 14, 1981; Bulletin of the University of Pittsburgh, Pitt Admissions, December 1980; Final Admissions Statistics 81-1, October 1, 1980; Office of Admissions Three-year Comparison; School of Social Work Weekly Statistics, February 12, 1980; Allocations for Campus Based Programs for Fiscal 1981, July 15, 1980; Campus Based Aid Programs Comparison of FY1980 and FY1981 Funding; Official notice of funding for the University of Pittsburgh's allocation of Federal funds to operate one or more of the campus-based student financial aid programs, May 1980; Approval of the application for a Law Enforcement Education Program, September 30, 1980; Substantial increase of 60% of financial aid for the students, September 15, 1980; and Comparison of Awarded Aid for FY1980 and FY1981, August 27, 1980,
    - Admissions and Student Aid (Box 16, Folder 7.15b)
      "Eating the Seed Corn" and "Sacred Cows, Colleges, and Costs" by Rhodes, March 1981; "Bulletin," Pitt Admissions, December 1980; Fall Term-Final Report, Office of Admissions, September 26, 1980; Allocations for Campus Based Programs for Fiscal 1981; Thank you for scholarship assistance from Mine Safety Appliances Company, October 2, 1980; Comparison of Awarded for Fiscal 1980 and Fiscal 1981; Approved application for a Law Enforcement Education Program award, September 3, 1980; Report on the legislation concerning standardized tests, August 12, 1980; Approximate costs for a Pennsylvania resident entering the University of Pittsburgh as a full-time freshman in September 1980; "University of Pittsburgh Office of Admissions and Student Aid, Five Year Review of Student Aid Programs," Fall 1980; Affirmative action concerns, February 10, 1981; College Entrance Examination Board Annual Business Meeting of the Middle States Regional Assembly, February 5, 1981; Cooperative Institution Research Program, March 24, 1981; and Analysis of freshmen applicant population and completion of two or more years in the same language.
    - Faculty Development (Box 16, Folder 7.17)
      Brochure, Conference on the Enhancement of Teaching in the Research University; Faculty Seminar Series, May 12, 1981; Academic Support Services, March 2, 1981; National Teaching Awards, April 22, 1981; New Faculty Orientation, April 1981; Annual Progress Report from the Office of Faculty Development; Report of the Office of Faculty Development's activities, August 4, 1980; Teaching Development Grants to Faculty, November 1980; Grants for Research and Study Toward Improved Teaching, September 1980; "Handbook for Teaching Assistants"; Institutional Portions of the Shell Graduate Grants, July 2, 1980; and Summary of the Teaching Development Grant Program FY1979-1980.
    - University Honors Program (Box 16, Folder 7.19)
      "A Proposal to United States Steel Corporation for Programmatic Endowment Support of the University Honors Program at the University of Pittsburgh"; "The University Honors Program Formal Course Offerings," Fall and Winter 1981; "University Honors Program, An Academic Program for Capable and Motivated Students"; Committee to Select Undergraduate Teaching Fellowships, December 10, 1980; UhpWords, A Publication of the University Honors Program, University of Pittsburgh; Responsibility Center Major Accomplishments, 1981; "The development of honors approaches in American higher education"; University Honors Program soliciting proposals for Winter Term 1982; New UHP-Phi Beta Kappa Option, July 18, 1980; and "UHP, The Honors Center."
    - Measurement and Evaluation (Box 17, Folder 7.20.)
    - University External Studies (Box 17, Folder 7.21)
      Newsletter for the External Studies Program, "The Extension Choral"; Draft, Foreword to "Telecommunications and Higher Education" by Posvar; Meeting with Warner Cable, December 12, 1980; Results of Successful Leadership Exercise, December 4, 1980.
    - Aerospace Studies (Box 17, Folder 7.22)
      Board of Directors of the PPG Industries Foundation approval of a pledge of $300,000 to the Resources For the Eighties campaign; Cadet Colonel Mines to receive the Chancellor's Award in recognition of his overall superior performance, February 9, 1981; Air Force ROTC Agreement and Curriculum; Schools and Programs for CAS Students Aerospace Studies (AFROTC); Seminar in U.S. Military Forces; Development of Air Power, Department of Aerospace Studies; Aerospace Studies, Management and Leadership; and Syllabus for American Defense Policy and Strategy and Defense Policy Making.
    - Military Sciences (Box 17, Folder 7.23)
      Resolution which urges universities having ROTC programs in its school curriculum to grant graduation credits for all ROTC courses taken by a student, 6/12/81; Continuation of making normal faculty and staff appointments to AFROTC positions without recourse to personal interviews and require a site visit for a potential PAS when deemed necessary; Plan to eliminate a discriminatory and unfair practice against ROTC students at the University, June 12, 1981; Annual Army ROTC Commissioning Ceremony, April 17, 1981; Increase in ROTC enrollment increase in ROTC enrollment, April 20, 1981; Proposal for ROTC Accreditation, January 14, 1981; AFROTC Position on Contractual Factors in Credit and Agreement, December 1980; First ROTC Region 1980 Advanced Camp Final Report, August 28, 1980; and Application and Agreement for the Establishment of a Senior Air Force Reserve Officers' Training Corps Unit.
    - University Women's Center (Box 17, Folder 7.24)